Guide to the Pennsylvania State University, Department of Animal Nutrition records 00044
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
Pennsylvania State University, Department of Animal Nutrition records
1859-1979
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
00044
99 Linear Feet
The collection contains central farm reports, barn books, farm account books, record book of crops and plots, tobacco experiments, financial records and account books, faculty notebooks, glass plate slides, blueprints and drawings for labs and equipment, fruit charts and articles, and correspondence generated by the Animal Nutrition Institute, which operated at the Pennsylvania State University from 1907 until 1946, when it officially became the Department of Animal Nutrition.
Biographical / Historical
In 1887, the United State's Congress passed the Hatch Act, which provided money for the establishment of Agricultural Experiment Stations at Land Grant Institutions. That same year, Henry P. Armsby was appointed as the Director of the Pennsylvania State College Agricultural Experiment Station. In 1898, in conjunction with the Bureau of Animal Industry of the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Armsby began investigations into animal nutrition. In 1902, with the assistance of Professors Jons A. Fries and I. Thornton Osmond, Armsby designed, constructed, and installed the Respiration Calorimeter, a device that monitored the metabolism of cattle. It was the only one of its kind in the country.
During its September 19, 1905 meeting, the Pennsylvania State College Board of Trustees concluded that it was necessary for the School of Agriculture to create a new department, to be called the Institute of Animal Nutrition. On July 1, 1907, Armsby become the Director of the newly-formed Institute. The Institute was reorganized to function as a department in 1933, although the name was retained until 1946 when it officially became the Department of Animal Nutrition.
Scope and Contents
Farm reports, account books, and record books of crops and plots, the earliest being an 1859 plot diary of the Superintendent of the Eastern plots, Thomas M. Harvey, help make up this collection. Experimental records involving steer, cows and rats are part of the material that goes with faculty notebooks, charts, and analysis pertaining to the intake and output of the animals. Glass slide negatives depicting educational programs pertaining to the growing of various plants and vegetables, as well as farm animal management, are also included.
Faculty correspondence going back to H.P. Armsby's 1906 letters to/from faculty members from the Penn State Agricultural College, as well as other agricultural colleges at universities such as Wisconsin, Minnesota and Illinois, are in the collection. There is also correspondence with organizations such as the Institute of American Meat packers, the American Society of Agriculture Engineers, the Pennsylvania Game Commission, and the Federal Bureau of Animal Industries. The collection also contains photographs and slides taken at various agricultural shows and programs showing members of the Future Farmers of America, tool and equipment demonstrations, faculty members, and workshop sites.
Volumes of the Agricultural Experiment Station Report from 1888-1906 are included in the collection, as well as Agricultural Bulletins from 1882-1886. The collection provides a rich history of the agricultural research on Penn State's University Park campus, both on plots of land as well as inside of the Armsby Respiration Calorimeter building.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 10 series: Administrative Files, Correspondence, Equipment, Experiments and Projects, Financial, Glass Lantern Photographic Slides, Notebooks/Record Books, Photographs, Publications, and Tests.
Animal nutrition -- Pennsylvania -- University Park
- Administrative Files, 1
  - Special O2 Results, undated (Box 2)
  - Details of Determination of CO2 and O2, undated (Box 2)
  - Details of Analysis Work, undated (Box 2)
  - An Improved Method of Computating etc., undated (Box 2)
  - Correction for the Total Heat Production, undated (Box 2)
  - Special Residual Samples, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Calibration of Meters, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Rat Colony Records, 1935-1939 (Box 9)
  - Rat Colony Records, 1943-1950 (Box 9)
  - The Energy Metabolism in Cattle, in Relation to the Plane of Nutrition, 1928 (Box 9)
  - Thermometer Readings, undated (Box 9)
  - Calibration of Air Meters, 1924 (Box 9)
  - Individual Feeding for the Comparative Feeding Trial, undated (Box 9)
  - Factors of Computation, 1922 (Box 12)
  - Thiamin and the Metabolism of Carbohydrate, Protein, and Fat, undated (Box 12)
  - Standard Methods and Procedures, 1925 (Box 12)
  - Errors and Corrections in the Direct Heat Measurement, 1926 (Box 12)
  - Respiration Measurements, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Tissot Metabolism Record, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Original Certificate of Standardization (U.S. Bureau of Standards), 1923 (Box 12)
  - Vinegar/Mineral Acids, undated (Box 14)
  - Research: Data/Measurements/Writings, undated (Box 14)
  - Corrected Net Energy Values, 1924 (Box 14)
  - Rate of Heat Production by a Steer (Graphs), undated (Box 14)
  - Average Daily Balance of Calcium and Protein (Graphs), undated (Box 14)
  - Table of Specific Heat of Water, undated (Box 17)
  - Notes on Keeping Records, undated (Box 17)
  - Technique in Pasture Research, 1933-1940 (Box 17)
  - Techniques for Nutrition Surveys, 1946 (Box 17)
  - Nutritive Value of Forage…, 1945 (Box 17)
  - Progress Reports, 1935-1939 (Box 17)
  - Progress Reports, 1944-1953 (Box 17)
  - Feeders Guide and Formulas for Meal Mixtures, 1942 (Box 17)
  - Data and Computations for a Biometric Study, 1915 (Box 17)
  - Analysis of Tobacco Leaves, 1946 (Box 17)
  - Compiling Data for Ventilation (Box 17)
  - Phosphorus Survey, Cattle, 1937 (Box 17)
  - Making Tables for Bulletins, undated (Box 17)
  - Active Projects--College of Agriculture, 1955 (Box 17)
  - College Regulations, 1956 (Box 17)
  - College Regulations, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Conference Program: N'East Div. of Ameri. Fisheries Society, 1953 (Box 17)
  - Analytical Methods, undated (Box 17)
  - Minerals in Pyroxide Deficiency, undated (Box 27)
  - A Comparison of Nitrogen and Energy Determinations………Cattle Feces, undated (Box 27)
  - Nitrogen/Ether Extract/Iron Determinations, undated (Box 27)
  - Calibration of Meters by Oxygen, 1927, 1941 and 1946 (Box 27)
  - The Use of Preservatives to Prevent Loss of Nutrition from Cow Excreta, 1930 (Box 27)
  - Questionaire - Evaluation of Research and Graduate Study Programs…..in AG, 1958 (Box 27)
  - Abstract by Joel Axelson, 1940 (Box 27)
  - The Study of the Growth of Steers (Thesis by Fred S. Putney), 1908 (Box 30)
  - Metabolism of Inorganic Ash (Thesis by Donald C. Cochrane), 1921 (Box 30)
  - Lignin and Cutin on the Digestibility of Crude Fiber (Thesis by Charles D. Jeffries), 1922 (Box 30)
  - Energy in Milk Production and Body Increase in Cows, undated (Box 30)
  - Maintenance Requirements of Dry Cows, undated (Box 30)
  - Tables for Correction for Bore of Beckmann, undated (Box 30)
  - Commercial Potato Production in N'Eastern States, 1926 (Box 30)
  - Composition of Dry Matter, undated (Box 30)
  - Methods for Making out Printed Forms, undated (Box 30)
  - Digestibility/Metabolizability of Feeding Stuffs, undated (Box 30)
  - The Use... of a New…Respiration Chamber, undated (Box 30)
  - Drying Urine, Feces and Food Stuffs, 1904 (Box 30)
  - Inventory of items bought by the US Department of Ag for the PS College, 1904 (Box 30)
  - Directions for using the Spirometer, 1931 (Box 30)
  - Computing Ventilation, undated (Box 30)
  - Calibration of Air Meters, December 1911 and October 1919 (Box 30)
  - The Determination of Ammonia Nitrogen, 1914 (Box 30)
  - Notes on Determination of Energy, undated (Box 30)
  - Notes on Methods of Analysis, undated (Box 30)
  - Mechanical Seperation of Feces and Urine, undated (Box 30)
  - Computations and Notes on Energy Values, Ventilation, Heat Production ….., 1925-1927 (Box 30)
  - Analysis of Dog Chow (Box 30)
  - Gaseous Exchange - Heat Production -Metabolism of Protiens, undated (Box 30)
  - Memorandum of Understanding: PS College and the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1922 (Box 30)
  - Abstracts/Reports: Measuring Nutritive Energy of Farm Feeds, 1925-1926 (Box 30)
  - Respiration Calorimeter Methods, undated (Box 30)
  - Data for Tables and Graphs, 1948 (Box 30)
  - Maintenance Requirements of Cattle for Protein, undated (Box 30)
  - Revised Net Energy Values of Feeding Stuffs for Cattle, undated (Box 30)
  - The Protein Katabolism of Fasting Dry Cows, undated (Box 30)
  - Summaries - Notes- Cited Literature, undated (Box 30)
  - Nutrition and Heat Loss, undated (Box 30)
  - Mixed Rations, undated (Box 30)
  - Effects of Nutrients on Rats, undated (Box 30)
  - Energy Cost of Food Utilization, undated (Box 30)
  - Feeding Standards - Editorial Review, undated (Box 30)
  - Bibliography, undated (Box 30)
  - Influence of the Plane of Nutrition on Heat Disposal by Cattle, undated (Box 30)
  - Position and Metabolism of Fasting Cattle, undated (Box 30)
  - Minute Book of the East PA Lab Farm Club, 1872 (Box 40)
  - Lehigh Chemical Society Meeting Minutes, 1920-1932 (Box 41)
  - Wood/Bark/Leaves Study, undated (Box 49)
  - Research Proposal - Problems Encountered by PA. Mink Producers, 1965 (Box 49)
  - PA. Department of AG. - Agents Reports, 1904 (Box 49)
  - Testimony and Affidavit of Frear on Spirituous Liquids, undated (Box 53)
  - Reports on AES to USDA, 1895-1899 (Box 53)
  - Reports on AES to USDA, 1895-1906 (Box 53)
  - Alcohol Use Experiences, 1889-1896 (Box 53)
  - Appointments and Contracts, 1894-1906 (Box 53)
  - Building Plans, 1901 (Box 53)
  - Expositions - Louisiana Purchase, Colombian, 1893-1909 (Box 53)
  - Fertilizer Records - Transfer Controversy, 1889-1904 (Box 53)
  - Roads - Civil Engineering, 1890 (Box 53)
  - Sharpless, P. M. - Controversy, 1897-1898 (Box 53)
  - Thomas M. Harvey Diary, 1859-1860 (Box 54)
  - Horticulture Club Scrapbook, 1987-1988 (Box 57)
  - Department of Agricultural and Bio Chemistry Scrapbook, 1942-1959 (Box 57)
  - Posters - Steer and Cows (17 x 19), 1945 (Box 58)
  - Temperature Charts - (10 Readings over a 1 week period), 1947 (Box 58)
  - Fruit Charts and Articles, 1861-1871 (Box 58)
  - Central Farm Report, 1869-1870 (Box 58)
  - Poster - PA. Assoc. "State Star Farmers", undated (Box 58)
  - Charts, undated (Box 59)
  - Experiment Charts from Calorimeter (Box 60)
- Correspondence, 2
  - Correspondence, 1913-1959 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1943 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Univ. of Illinois (American Society of Animal Production), 1922-1934 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes - West Virgiia Univ., 1943-1948 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: J. McKeen Cattell (Editor of the Science Press), 1911-1941 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Nutrition Lab (Carnegie Institute of Washington), 1908-1938 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: North Dakota Agricultural College, 1920-1944 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Warren E. Collins, 1924-1938 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: California Vegetable Concentrates Inc., 1932-1941 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Utah Agricultural College, 1920-1924 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Department of Commerce and Labor, 1910-1927 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Holland/Netherlands, 1935-1948 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: R.W. Swift, 1946-1960 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: R.W. Swift/J.K. Loosli, 1955-1957 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes/G. Bohstedt, 1922-1942 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes/G.A. Brown, 1929-1937 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes/J. Alquier, 1929-1936 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes/R.M. Bethke, 1935-1944 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes/Sam Brody, 1924-1946 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Bennett, L.J., 1938-1942 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Alex Black, 1947-1962 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes, 1920-1949 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes and J.F. Lyman, 1925-1944 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: E.B. Forbes and H. E. Longenecker, 1944-1945 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: Western Experimental Farm, undated (Box 40)
  - Correspondence: University of Kentucky, 1941-1945 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of Illinois, 1935-1955 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of Minnesota, 1929-1941 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of New Hampshire, 1954-1955 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of Missouri, 1921-1946 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of Wisconsin, 1914-1945 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1943-1952 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Vermont Agricultural Extension Station, 1930-1950 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas, 1910-1939 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: H.P. Armsby/J.F. Lyman, 1917-1921 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: University of California, 1927-1957 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: H.P. Armsby/J.P. Welsh (Appointment of Armsby), 1906 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, 1925-1943 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Iodine Educ. Bureau, Inc., 1931-1943 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Institute of American Meat Packers, 1922-1940 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: American Society of Agricultural Engineers, 1924-1941 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Larrowe Milling Co., 1911-1944 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Dr. Alberto Findanza, 1953 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: U.S. Government (Report on Pasture Research in N'East U.S.), 1953-1955 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Bureau of Animal Industry, 1924-1941 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Bureau of Animal Industry, 1950-1955 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: War Department, 1941-1944 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: Inter-Office, 1940-1963 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: American Journal of Physiology, 1910-1936 (Box 52)
  - Corresondence: Department of Justice - Bureau of Prisons, 1932 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence: PA. Game Commission, 1945, 1952-1956 (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, 1887-1889 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence Record Book (Henry Armsby), 1886-1887 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence: Melon Institute of Industrial Research, 1929-1932 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1964 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: National Research Council, 1923-1947 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: H.P. Armsby, 1917-1922 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: H.K. Schilling, 1951-1957 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: The Quaker Oats Corp., 1928-1937 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: Purina Mills, 1912-1944 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: Dr. S. W. Fletcher, 1928-1935 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: Job Applications, 1940-1950 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence: Dr. H.H. Mitchell, 1926-1949 (Box 39)
- Equipment, 3
  - Directions for Operating Special Potentiometer, undated (Box 2)
  - Resistance Thermometers in Calorimetry, undated (Box 2)
  - New Oxygen Apparatus Data, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Directions for Using Sonden's CO2 Device, undated (Box 2)
  - Air Analysis of Carpenter Apparatus, 1929 (Box 12)
  - Calibration of (Tissot) Spirometer, 1942 and 1954 (Box 9)
  - Calibration of Oxygen Apparatus (Carpenter), 1928 (Box 9)
  - Observations in Air Analysis (Carpenter Apparatus), 1931 (Box 9)
  - Respiration Measurements - Tissot - (9 separate folders with various subjects), 1953-1955 (Box 27)
  - The Bicycle Ergometer, 1942 (Box 27)
  - The Respiration Calorimeter, 1958 (Box 27)
  - Air Analysis by Carpenter Apparatus, 1929 (Box 27)
  - Wooden Gauge to calculate Air/Water/Room Temperature (Box 57)
  - Respiration Calorimeter, 1900-1903 (Box 30)
  - Buildings, Equipment, 1885-1907 (Box 53)
- Experiments and Projects, 4
  - Experiment 216, undated (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1016, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Experiment 936, undated (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1089, undated (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1019 - Book #1, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1016 - Layout of Grass Plots, 1943-1948 (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1016-C, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Experiment 1019, undated (Box 2)
  - Experiment 236 - Iron in Meats, undated (Box 2)
  - Experiment 221F, 1921-1922 (Box 2)
  - Experiment 241 - Periods 1-5, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Periods 7 - 12, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Periods 1-5 - Ventilation, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Periods 7-13 - Ventilation, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Steer Measurements-Hide area, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Tables - Periods 10-13, undated (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Tables - Per. 7 Fasting (steer 17), undated (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Tables - Per. 8 Fasting (steer 85), undated (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Tables - Per. 9 Fasting (steer 17), undated (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Steer 17, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Record of Feed/Water/Temp., 1928-1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Log Book, 1928-1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - Institute of Animal Nutrition, 1928-1929 (Box 3)
  - Experiment 241 - (Steer 85), 1927-1928 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 - Preliminary, 1928-1929 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 244 - Chicks, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 and 244 - Chick Weights, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 and 244 - Log Book, 1931 (Box 6)
  - Experiments 243 & 244 - Analytical data, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 and 244 - Periods 1-4, 1928-1929 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 and 244 - Periods 1-4 (Sample List), 1928-1929 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 243 and 244 - Record of Feed and Excreta, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Periods 1-15 - Cow 2, 1929-1930 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Periods 1-11 - Cow 3, 1929-1930 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Daily Averages - Intake/Output, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Log Book, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Summary of Balances, 1932 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Mineral Metabolism Tables, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Periods 6-16, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Tables, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Period 1-5, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Gross Efficiency of Cows, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Correction of TDN for error in Ash, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Milk Production, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Digestibility of Dry Matter, undated (Box 6)
  - Experiment 248 - Ingest/Output per Period, 1929-1930 (Box 6)
  - Experiment 259 I - Analytical Data, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 I - Feed Records, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 I - Weekly Preliminary Records, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 I - Tables, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 I and K - Final Tables, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 I, J, L and M (Log Book), 1933 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 K - Log Book (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 K - Respiratory Quotient, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 K - Analytical Sheets, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 K - Feed and Live Weights, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 K - Tables, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 L - Phosphorus Deficiency, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 G - Vitamin A-Feed Sheets, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 H - Vitamin G, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 M - Sodium Deficiency, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 G and H - Analytical Sheets, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 J - Analytical Sheets, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 M and O - Analytical Sheets, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 H - Tables/Feed Records/Live Weight, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 H - References, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 - Metabolism of Vitamin Deficient Rate, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 - Vitamin G (B2) Concentrate, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 - Fe Experiment, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 O - Tables (Final Results) Anemio, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 M - Tables, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 G - Tables - Carotene, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 J - Weekly Records, Feed Sheets, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 Q - Phosphorous Deficiency, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 R - Tables (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 T - Analytical Sheets (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 T - Feed Sheets and Live Weights, 1938 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 T - Tables, 1938 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 U - Tables, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 U - Preliminary Feeding Records, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 U - Feed and Live Weight, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 U - Analytical Sheets, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Experiment 259 V - Feed Sheets/Chloride Deficiency, undated (Box 8)
  - Experiment 238 Period I - Steer 47, 1926 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period I - Steer 47, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period II - Steer 36, 1926 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period IIa - Steer 36, 1926 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period 3 - Steer 47, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period IV - Steer 36, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period VI - Steer 36, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period VII - Steer 47, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period VIII - Steer 36, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period IX - Steer 47, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period X - Steer 36, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period XII - Steer 36 (Fasting), 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Period 11 - Steer 47 (Fasting), 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 Periods 11 and 12 (Fasting), undated (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - Tables - Set #2, undated (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - The Institute of Animal Nutrition, 1926-1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - Daily Food and Live Weight, 1926 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - Results of Analysis (Steer 36 and 47), undated (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - Surface Area of Hide (Steer 47), 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - Intestinal Contents of A.H. Hereford Steer, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 238 - How Position Affects the Rate of Metabolism of Fasting Cattle, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Experiment 240 - Tables - Set #2, undated (Box 12)
  - Experiment 240 - Tube Weights, 1928 (Box 12)
  - Experiment 240 - Steer 60, 1927-1928 (Box 12)
  - Experiment 240 - Steer 57, 1927-1928 (Box 12)
  - Experiment 240 - Methods of Computing Net Energy Values, undated (Box 12)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Reproduction & Lactation - Original Feed & Growth Data, 1952-53 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Consumption Charts, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Breeding Records - Reproduction & Lactation, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Reproduction & Lactation - Antibiotics, 1951-53 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Fat in Growth and Longevity, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - The Effect of High Levels of Terramycin or Streptomycin...., August 23, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Feed and Weight (Strep. and Terra.), 1953 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - 1st, 2nd and 3rd Generation, 1952 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - CHO Diet/Female, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - Fat Diet/Female, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - Control Diet/Female, 1949-52 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - CHO Diet/Male, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - Fat Diet/Male, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - Control Diet/Male, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 - Longevity - Breeding Record of Rat Colony, 1948-1949 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - 1st and 2nd Parturition & Lactation, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 D - Male Fertility Data, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1088 R - Breeding Records - Reproduction & Lactation, 1949-51 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1089 A - Thiouracil-Growth and Feed Consumption Sheets, 1947-1949 (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1089 B - Thiouracil - Growth and Feed Consumption Sheets, undated (Box 13)
  - Experiment 1160 - Blank CO2 and HO2 Tests, Feb.1956 and Jan.1958 (Box 15)
  - Experiment 1160 - Calibration of Carpenter Apparatus, 1952 and 1954 (Box 15)
  - Experiment 1160 - Period 1 - Low Protein, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Experiment 1160 - Period 2 - High Protein, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Experiment 1160 - Period 3 - Low Protein, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Experiment 1160 - Period 4 - High Protein, 1957 (Box 15)